[Music]
the stoa
is a digital campfire where we cohere in
dialogue
about what matters most at the knife's
edge of what's happening now
welcome to the stowa oh
i'm peter lindbergh steward of the stoa
stow is a place for us to cohere and
dialogue about what matters most at the
nice edge of this
moment and what matters most is a
conversation on
metamodern masculinity
so today we have aaron rodgerson
aaron is he's a host co-host of a golden
shadow podcast
which is an exploration of philosophy
spirituality and self-help through an
evolutionary
in-depth psychology lens it's also
working on a book and a new youtube
channel that deals with depth psychology
and jungian thought
and then uh we're talking about
masculinity on kind of a private zoom
call
and he suggested having a conversation
on
on it a meta modern masculinity
is the the complications and the
confusions on what it means to be
a man in general and what does it mean
to be a masculine man
um so yeah i'm like let's have a session
and have some jazzy title called
modern masculinity screen for all the
weirdos and uh
and let's run with it so that being said
uh
we're here for about an hour uh we're
only gonna record the intro
of aaron and then we're gonna stop and
we're gonna have uh conversations
uh we might go over uh seven to seventy
five minutes tyson has a uh
event after this so no more than 90
minutes but we might hear it be
a little bit longer than 90 minutes
so or 60 minutes i should say that being
said
i will allow iron to admit himself and
take him in
thanks peter for that great intro music
that was
his idea not mine but i enjoyed it very
much
very good um so yeah my name's aaron uh
today we're talking about meta-modern
masculinity and the goal with this event
is to create a
collaborative space where we can
dialogue about masculinity and what it
means to be a man
because from my perspective this
conversation isn't happening very
effectively
in the public space so again i'm not
here to lecture
but i'm going to give a brief
introduction for a few minutes and then
we're going to have a discussion
afterwards so what do i mean by this
term
meta-modern masculinity so metamodernism
is
an evolving term that carries diverse
implications
but to put it simply meta modernism
integrates
the project of modernism with its
postmodern critique
it transcends and includes both
perspectives
taking what's useful and discarding
what's not uh the idealistic
naive child of modernism develops into
the ironic
cynical teenager of post-modernism which
in turn develops into the wise
adult of metamodernism who hasn't buried
or repressed the idolistic child
or the skeptical teenager but has
integrated them both into his being
so when it comes to masculinity uh we
have these modern ideals
of strength stoicism and warriorship
men are the breadwinners they're the
providers they're impervious resilient
independent in control and in charge
modernism frames this
as simply being the nature of men it's
grounded in biology
the post-modern critique of the modern
man is that perhaps strength
stoicism and warriorship is not only
unhelpful
but unhealthy perhaps masculinity is not
biological but socially constructed
and thrust upon men making them
tyrannical repressive of their emotions
and
violent perhaps we should be questioning
this modern notion of manhood
or even throw it out the meta modern man
mediates between the two so what we call
masculinity is partly biological
and it's partly a social construct
perhaps we have impoverished and
traumatized young men
by pushing them too hard to be tough
competitive and independent
um conversely perhaps we've been
ignoring
the biology of men banishing their
masculinity from the public space
into the shadows where their repressed
wounded manhood
lashes out violently in inappropriate
ways at inappropriate times
so where the modern project is one of
rationality and science
and the post-modern project is one of
skepticism
the meta-modern project is spiritual
it's a project of wisdom
of balance of transcendence rather than
trying to become
the modern king or the post-modern
philosopher
he becomes the philosopher king
so we live in a time of great
uncertainty but the meta-modern man is
brave enough to journey into the
uncharted lands of the 21st century
and become a father to the unknown
future
so what does meta-modern masculinity
mean
what does it look like i don't know and
you probably don't know either
um that's why we're having a discussion
so my hope is that we enter this space
with a
collective unknowingness and together
move towards a place
of knowingness through integrating the
different perspectives of this community
um hopefully this conversation will be
the first of many we'll see
um i think there's a lot to talk about
here but for today
we're just going to start with something
basic
so this is going to be collaborative um
it's going to be a discussion we're
going to break out into
partners groups of two as a kind of
icebreaker
and the goal is to sort of get into the
collaborative mode
through this so i'm going to give you a
prompt and
the prompt is what is masculinity
very basic and you can interpret that
how you wish
what is masculinity and in the breakout
rooms with your partner
one person is going to answer the prompt
for two minutes and then
you'll um sorry the second partner is
going to mirror for one minute
then you'll switch and the second
partner will answer the prompt for two
minutes
followed by the other one mirroring them
back for one minute so for a total of
six minutes
okay and mirroring means paraphrasing
back
to the speaker what you think they just
tried to express so that the speaker can
confirm
that you understood them does that make
sense
the idea is to actively listen and to
try and embody the other person's
perspective
so are there any questions about
mirroring or what we're about to do
six minutes of partners so can they
unmute themselves
peter yeah all right are you gonna throw
a timer on there for us
i will i'm gonna send in instructions
into the breakout room it's going to
give you timers
and let you know what to do
any other questions yeah if your mic is
not working
you can write into the chat and if your
partner isn't
there or is not participating or you
don't want to participate for whatever
reason
you can just come back into the main
breakout session and uh
um let's see do i have the power to do
breakout rooms
peter yes i'll stop recording